{"tossups": [{"question": "This man defeated an opponent denounced as \u201cthe continental liar from the state of Maine.\u201d That opponent\u2019s supporters responded with the chant, \u201cMa, Ma, where\u2019s my Pa?\u201d to publicize this man\u2019s relationship with Maria Helpin. This man sent in Federal troops to end the Pullman Strike but lost his party\u2019s nomination for president to William Jennings Bryan due to his ineffective response to the Panic of 1893. For ten points, name this only U.S. president to serve non-consecutive terms.", "answer": "Grover<b> Cleveland</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "One poem focusing on this conflict describes how \u201cleaves / Flying, plunge and expire\u201d and how the central figures \u201cfeed the grass row after rich row.\u201d In another poem about this conflict, Robert Lowell described a monument near the \u201cOld South Boston Aquarium\u201d dedicated to a hero of this conflict named Robert Gould Shaw who led the siege of Fort Wagner in South Carolina. For ten points, name this war that was the subject of Allen Tate\u2019s \u201cOde to the Confederate Dead.\u201d", "answer": "U.S.<b> Civil</b> War", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Poetry"}, {"question": "One participant in this event claimed \u201cI am in hell. I am in hell\u201d after being reminded that he knew the victim\u2019s children. A man named John Adams was found alive years after this event, as was its leader\u2019s son, Thursday October. After this event, one person sailed over 6,000 kilometers to Timor. This 1789 event was led by Fletcher Christian, who stopped at Tahiti before settling at Pitcairn Island. For ten points, name this revolt against Captain William Bligh by his crew.", "answer": "Mutiny on the<em><b> Bounty</b></em> (accept any answer relating to an insurrection, overthrow, revolt, etc. on the HMS<em><b> Bounty</b></em>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This location is named after a pilot who became the first navy serviceman to win the Medal of Honor in World War Two. Midway Airport serves the same metropolitan area as this airport which is near the Des Plaines [dess planes] River. For ten points, name this airport that serves a major U.S. city in Illinois.", "answer": "Chicago<b> O\u2019Hare</b> International Airport (prompt on<b> ORD</b>) Page 1", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}, {"question": "This country\u2019s former president, Leonid Kuchma, tried to rig a 2004 election that sparked nationwide protests in the Orange Revolution. The shooting down of a Malaysia Airlines flight occurred as part of this country\u2019s War in Donbass. Protests in this country\u2019s Donetsk Oblast and bombings of cities like Kharkiv and Odessa were part of a campaign in the south and east of this country advocating Russia\u2019s annexation of Crimea. For ten points, name this Eastern European country governed from Kiev.", "answer": "<b> Ukraine</b>", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {}, {"question": "Four days after a series of events in this city, a similar event was avoided in Hanover thanks to the findings of a paramedic. After the events in this city, a grey Volkswagen Polo with foreign license plates was recovered which served as evidence that led to a raid on the Molenbeek [moh-lun-bek] area of Brussels. The events in this city occurred despite heightened security following an attack earlier that year in this city at the offices of<em> Charlie Hebdo</em>. An explosion during the events in this city occurred outside a stadium where Francois Hollande was watching a football game. For ten points, what European capital was shaken by a series of terrorist attacks in November, 2015?", "answer": "<b> Paris</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This event was slightly delayed on its first day, July 19, 1848, due to the locked doors in the Wesleyan Methodist Chapel. Thomas M\u2019Clintock read several passages of William Blackstone\u2019s<em> Commentaries</em>, and Frederick Douglass gave a speech at this event. The Declaration of Sentiments was drafted at this event which had been organized by Elizabeth Cady Stanton. For ten points, name this meeting in New York concerning women\u2019s rights.", "answer": "<b> Seneca Falls</b> Convention Page 2", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This man appointed the \u201cOhio Gang\u201d to positions in his administration including Attorney General Harry Daugherty, who obstructed the investigation into the most notorious scandal of this man\u2019s administration. That scandal involved the acceptance of loans from Edward Doheny by this man\u2019s Secretary of the Interior, Albert B. Fall, in exchange for drilling rights. The Teapot Dome Scandal took place during the administration of, for ten points, this president who died in office of a heart attack and was succeeded by Calvin Coolidge.", "answer": "Warren G(amaliel)<b> Harding</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "During the 1964 World\u2019s Fair, this man developed the \u201cGreat Moments with Mr. Lincoln\u201d exhibit. Charles Mintz took the rights for a character named \u201cLucky Rabbit\u201d that was created by this man. Art Babbitt helped lead a 1941 strike against this man on charges of anti-Semitism that others roundly denounced. With Ub Iwerks, this man developed a character that debuted in<em> Steamboat Wilie</em>, and Nikita Khruschev was denied access to one of this man\u2019s theme parks. For ten points, name this animator and business mogul who developed Mickey Mouse.", "answer": "Walter \u201cWalt\u201d<b> Disney</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Film"}, {}, {"question": "This country was aided by Operation Black Magic, in which the United States supplied F-86 Sabres to grant this country air superiority in one conflict. This country was forced into another conflict when this country\u2019s Matsu Islands were shelled. During one crisis, a neighbor attempted to intimidate supporters of Lee Teng-hui by firing missiles dangerously close to this country\u2019s shoreline. For ten points, name this island country that faced three namesake straits crises with its northern neighbor, China.", "answer": "<b> Taiwan</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "This person replied to ABC news reporter Martha Raddatz by saying, \u201cSo?\u201d when being questioned about war support. During the Halloween Massacre, this man replaced Donald Rumsfeld as Chief of Staff. Colin Powell claimed that this man\u2019s advisor David Addington was responsible for NSA wiretaps on American citizens. The Plame Affair led this man\u2019s Chief of Staff, Scooter Libby, to resign. This man, who shot Harry Whittington on a hunting trip, previously served as CEO of Halliburton. For ten points, name this Vice President under George W. Bush.", "answer": "Richard \u201cDick\u201d<b> Cheney</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "A famous one of these places is named for a French aviation pioneer and fighter pilot, Roland Garros. Another of these places was known as the<em> Jeu de Paume</em> at the time it served as the venue for the 1789 meeting place of members of the Third Estate. One of these in Flushing Meadows is named after Arthur Ashe, while another in England saw champions like Andre Agassi and Bjorn Borg win titles on grass surfaces. For ten points, name these sporting venues, one of which saw a namesake \u201coath\u201d taken during the French Revolution.", "answer": "<b> Tennis court</b>s", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {}, {"question": "In exchange for aiding this event, William Fessenden was offered the ministership to Great Britain. This event would have led to the ascension of Benjamin Wade, had it not been prevented by a decisive vote from Terrence Ross. This event was prompted when its central participant hired Lorenzo Thomas to replace Edwin Stanton as Secretary of War, violating the Tenure of Office Act. For ten points, name this 1868 event in which the 17th U.S. president faced being removed from office.", "answer": "<b> Impeach</b>ment of<b> Andrew Johnson</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>A joint military plan between this country and Germany known as Operation Silver Fox aimed to take control of a set of nickel mines in this country\u2019s province of Petsamo. The Continuation War was fought between this country and an eastern neighbor. The term (+) Molotov Cocktail was coined in this country in opposition to the foreign policies leading to the Winter War. During World War Two, soldiers from this country often built makeshift (*)</b> saunas in the field. For ten points, name this country with its capital at Helsinki.", "answer": "Republic of<b> Finland</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>One legend says this man was born in and buried in Vienne, France. Various apocryphal tales suggest this man may have been crucified as a Christian martyr or forced by Nero</b> <b>to commit suicide in the Tiber. During (+)</b> <b>Passover, this man\u2019s citizens chose to release</b> <b>Barabbas from prison. This man replied \u201cWhat I have written, I have written\u201d in response to putting up a sign declaring a certain man (*)</b> \u201cKing of the Jews\u201d as that man was nailed to a cross. For ten points, name this prefect of Judaea who sentenced Jesus to death.", "answer": "Pontius<b> Pilate</b> (accept Pontius<b> Pilatus</b>) Page 9", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>The original sets for this work were designed by Nicholas Roerich, and grace notes in the opening lines of this work are used to imitate human voices. This work was the third by its composer that he created for Russian impresario Sergei Diaghilev, the founder of the</b> <b>(+)</b> <b>Paris-based Ballets Russes. Choreographed by Vaslav Nijinsky, this work ends with a</b> <b>Paris-based Ballets Russes. Choreographed by Vaslav Nijinsky, this work ends with a</b> <b>young girl dancing herself to death in a sacrifical ritual, and the Paris (*)</b> <b>young girl dancing herself to death in a sacrifical ritual, and the Paris (*)</b> premiere of this work caused a riot. For ten points, name this 1913 ballet depicting \u201cPagan Russia,\u201d composed by Igor Stravinsky.", "answer": "<em> The<b> Rite of Spring</b></em> (accept<em> Le<b> Sacre du printemps</b></em>)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Dance"}, {}, {}], "bonuses": []}